-[siren wailing in distance] -[footsteps]
‎我非常害怕出门
[woman 1] I am absolutely terrified of going outside.
‎我不会出去散步
I don't go outside for walks.
‎看到别人的时候 我会不自觉地想
When I see people, I automatically think
‎他们病了 还想传染给我
that they're sick and they want to get me sick.
‎我一直在疯狂地洗手
[woman 2] I've been washing my hands obsessively.
‎我会给家里的电灯开关
I've been disinfecting light switches
‎和门把手反复消毒
and doorknobs in my house multiple times a day.
‎我觉得四处都是威胁
[man] I see threats everywhere.
‎无论望向哪里 都能看到病毒微粒
Everywhere I look, I see virus particles.
‎在当前形势下 我们需要体验恐惧
We need to experience fear in this situation.
‎恐惧能帮助我们活下去
Fear is there to help us survive.
‎恐惧能让我们做好面对危险的准备
Fear is there to help us prepare for danger.
‎它会驱使我们遵守规则
[narrator] It drives us to follow the rules.
‎待在家里 勤洗手 戴口罩 保持距离
Staying home, washing our hands, wearing a mask, and keeping our distance.
‎但起初有益的恐惧会累积
But fear that starts out as productive can stack up.
‎我们不想让四个月大的女儿感染病毒
The anxiety that comes along with having a four-month-old
‎所以会非常焦虑
and not wanting her to get the virus.
‎（塔狄安娜）
[in Russian] My business has completely stopped dead, just halted.
‎（洛莉 印度）
[in English] Juggling household work, office work...
‎在家学习 必须把每件事都做到位
homeschooling... Just making sure every need is met.
‎（艾琳 意大利）
[in Italian] I regret not being able to attend the last semester of university.
‎我们有很多想见的人 ‎但现在显然不可能见到
[in English] We would love to see lots of people, obviously,
but that's an impossibility.
‎没人知道未来会发生什么 ‎一切都是不确定的
Nobody knows what's happening in the future. It's all very uncertain.
‎你不知道它在哪里 ‎什么时候会咬你一口
You don't know where it is and when it's going to bite you.
‎它…
It's...
‎非常强大
very powerful.
‎我们通过这件事明白了
I think that what we're seeing now
‎人与人之间的相似性多于差异
is that we are all more the same than we are different.
‎我们有相似的恐惧 ‎相似的希望 相似的梦想
We have, um, similar fears, similar hopes, similar dreams...
‎因为历史上很少有这样的时刻 ‎这么多人在面对同样的危机
[narrator] Because rarely in history
have so many of us faced the same crises all at once.
‎在美国 疫情爆发几个月后
In the US, a few months into the outbreak,
‎三分之一的人感觉到巨大心理困扰
a third of people were experiencing high psychological distress,
‎而在中国 一半医护人员患有抑郁症
and in China, half of the doctors and nurses reported depression.
‎有几乎一样多的人有焦虑症
Almost as many reported anxiety.
‎而在曾经的集体危机中
And in past collective crises,
‎比如恐怖袭击
like terrorist attacks,
‎自然灾害 或其他传染病
natural disasters, and other epidemics,
‎人们在长达一年多以后
people struggled with these kind of effects
‎仍在经历类似的折磨
even a year or more later.
‎我们很多人正在经历的压力
The stress many of us are experiencing right now
‎可能会在疫情结束之后 ‎仍伴随着我们
could stay with us long after the pandemic itself is over,
‎但其实有别的选择
but it doesn't have to.
‎应对是一种预防性的保健
Coping is preventative care.
‎我们今天做的小事情 ‎会在未来保护我们
Small things we do today can help protect us in the future.
‎所以应该怎么做呢？
So what does that look like?
‎我们如何应对？
How do we cope?
‎我希望人们别再恐惧 ‎我希望人们别再焦虑
I want the fear to stop. I want the anxiety to stop.
[sirens blaring]
[theme music playing]
‎肉体可以隔离 ‎但情感和社会交往不一定需要隔离
You can physically isolate, but you don't have to emotionally and socially isolate.
‎-嗨 爸爸 ‎-嗨
-Hi, Dad. -Hi.
[exhaling]
‎我们需要共同努力 解决这个问题
We have to work together to address this issue.
[knocking]
‎杂货配送
Grocery delivery.
‎疫情正在发生 我们不能被它打垮
This is happening. We can't let it bring us down.
-[all cheering] -I love my community...
‎我很喜欢我的社区 ‎我们好像是一体的
and I feel like we are one.
[theme music continues]
‎平静是你的休息状态
[narrator] Calmness is your resting state,
‎是一种平衡的状态
a state of balance.
‎压力则恰恰相反
And stress is the opposite.
‎应对意味着找回平衡
Coping means restoring that balance.
‎学习找回平衡 ‎应该对控制它的系统有所了解
So to learn how, it helps to understand the system that controls it.
‎当你的大脑觉察到威胁时
When your brain perceives a threat, it sounds an alarm,
‎它会通过你的神经系统发出一个警报
using your nervous system,
‎神经系统是一个网络 ‎能向你的全身快速传送电信号
a network of wires that zip electrical messages around your body.
‎自主神经系统是它的一部分 ‎能在不需要你思考的情况下
The autonomic nervous system is that part of it that takes care of things
‎自动处理一些事情
automatically for you without you thinking about it.
‎它将你的大脑和几乎所有 ‎主要器官连接在一起
[narrator] It connects your brain to nearly all your major organs,
‎可以将它分成两个对立的系统
and it can be divided into two opposing systems.
‎交感神经系统会向你的身体发出警报
The sympathetic nervous system
-tells your body when it's on high alert, -[animal growls]
‎而副交感神经系统 ‎会通知你的身体放松
while the parasympathetic nervous system tells your body when it's okay to relax.
‎一个像是油门
-One is like a gas pedal, -[car accelerating]
‎而另一个是刹车
and the other is the brakes.
[car braking]
‎当你平静的时候 它们会不断博弈
[narrator] When you're calm, they are in constant push and pull,
‎彼此制衡
keeping each other in check.
‎但当你焦虑的时候 ‎交感神经系统便会统揽大局
But when you're stressed, the sympathetic nerves take over.
‎你的肾上腺会释放压力激素： ‎肾上腺素和皮质醇
Your adrenal glands release stress hormones, adrenaline, and cortisol.
‎你的心率会上升
Your heart rate rises.
‎你的肝脏会向血液释放糖分 ‎让你精力旺盛
Your liver releases sugar into your blood, giving you a burst of energy.
‎你会呼吸加速 肌肉紧绷
Your breathing speeds up, muscles tense for action, and then,
‎当你完成战斗或逃跑 ‎你的身体会回归正常
once you're finished fighting or fleeing, your body goes back to normal.
‎问题在于
The problem is, it doesn't matter whether it's a physical threat
‎无论是面对现实威胁 ‎还是更抽象的威胁
or more abstract one.
‎你的大脑会做出完全一致的反应
Your brain will mobilize the exact same response.
‎而我们正在面对的威胁 ‎不是能逃过的那种
And the threats we're facing right now aren't the kind you can outrun.
‎当我早上意识到
When I found out in the morning
‎自己不得不去住院
that I was gonna have to be admitted to the hospital
‎而且会被隔离
and that I was gonna be admitted alone,
‎不能有任何人看望
that I wouldn't be able to have any visitors,
‎我感觉一切都崩塌了
I think all of it just came crashing down.
‎我开始抽泣和颤抖
I started sobbing and shaking
‎就像典型的恐慌症发作 我停不下来
and, I mean, kind of a classic panic attack. I couldn't stop.
‎焦虑症对我而言格外痛苦
It's been really tough for my anxiety, 'cause I have sickle cell disease.
‎我非常容易受到感染
I'm more prone to catching infection.
‎如果我患上新冠肺炎
And I don't really have, like,
‎我的耐受力不足以支撑我挺过来
the tolerance to be able to, like, stand COVID if I caught it.
‎新冠肺炎跟我学医时 ‎经历的任何情况都不同
This has been unlike anything I have ever experienced in my training.
‎我必须跟电话那头的家庭
To have to do all of these difficult conversations
‎进行各种艰难的对话
with families over the phone,
‎家庭成员无法守在深爱的家人的床边
for family members not to be at the bedside with their loved ones.
‎这实在是…
I mean, it's just been...
‎无以言表地艰难
incredibly difficult.
‎我们的身体和精神无法长期承受压力
Our bodies and minds weren't designed for chronic stress.
‎它们被设计来面对短时的压力源
They were designed for these kinds of short-term stressors,
‎所释放的肾上腺素和其他化学物质
and all of the adrenaline and other chemicals that are released
‎会随着战斗或逃跑而消耗殆尽
get worked out by the fighting or the fleeing.
‎如果你的身体无法采取行动应对危机
[van der Kolk] If there's nothing  your body can do to take care of things,
‎为了采取行动而释放的能量 ‎便会留在体内
then the energy to do something stays in your body,
‎然后被转化成焦虑
and it gets translated into agitation.
‎我们平时能做的缓解焦虑的活动
[narrator] And the things we normally do to ease the agitation
‎在疫情环境下很难做到
can be a lot harder during a pandemic.
‎视频聊天是很好 但效果不一样
Video chats are great, but it's... it's not the same.
‎面对面地与他人进行交流
That physical component of being, um...
‎是我们现在没办法做到的事情
connected to others is something that we just really don't have right now.
‎焦虑的时候 连平常能让我们 ‎舒服一些的事情都很难完成
[narrator] Even the things we can do to feel better
become more difficult when we're stressed.
‎经常会失眠 夜间焦虑 无法入睡
A lot of insomnia, a lot of anxiety at night, difficulty sleeping.
‎（帕布洛）
[in Spanish] I find myself having trouble falling asleep.
‎我最近的睡眠很糟糕
[in English] I've been sleeping pretty bad.
‎凌晨两点 我还是睡不着
2:00 a.m., and I can't sleep.
‎当我们焦虑的时候 常常难以入睡
[Levitin] It's often hard to sleep when we're stressed
‎因为我们血管里还流淌着肾上腺素
because we've got adrenaline coursing through our veins
‎它会让我们保持清醒
which serves to keep us awake.
‎还可能因为我们在左思右想 ‎大脑不愿意休眠
It also can be because we're ruminating.
Our brains won't turn off.
‎我没办法进行艺术创作
I can't really think about being creative
‎因为我会担心自己付不起账单
when I have to worry about how I'm gonna eventually have to pay some my bills,
‎疫情什么时候结束 或者我的健康 ‎和被传染的可能性
or when this stuff is gonna end, or my health and potentially catching it.
‎焦虑的大脑只关心一件事
[narrator] A stressed brain has one priority:
‎让你准备战斗或者逃跑
getting you ready to fight or flee.
‎所以应对的第一步 ‎就是说服你的大脑你很安全
So coping begins with convincing your brain that you're safe,
‎而最简单的方法就是
and the easiest way to do that is by...
‎（呼吸）
[deep inhale]
[exhale]
‎通常是由你的大脑来决定是否安全
[narrator] Usually it's your brain that decides when it's safe to relax.
‎但当你深呼吸的时候
But when you breathe deeply,
‎安全的信息会被传送回去
the message of safety gets passed back up the line,
‎你的副交感神经系统会更活跃
and your parasympathetic nerves become more active.
‎这就像是一个作弊码
It's like a cheat code, forcing your system back into balance.
‎这其实可以通过 ‎我们心跳的间隔来测量
We can actually measure this, too, through the gaps in our heartbeats.
‎当你平静的时候 间隔会更大
When you're calm, the gaps are more varied
‎因为你的油门和刹车在相互博弈
because of that push and pull between your gas pedal and your brakes.
‎你的心率变异性会更高 也就是HRV
You have a higher heart rate variability, or HRV.
‎但当你的交感神经系统接管后
But when your sympathetic nervous system takes over,
‎心跳间隔会变得更短促 更有规律
the spaces become shorter and more regular,
‎心率变异性会低很多
a much lower HRV.
‎让我们试试
So let's try it.
‎吸气五秒
Breathe in for five.
‎保持住
Hold it.
‎呼气五秒
Breathe out for five.
[exhales]
‎一般人一分钟会呼吸12到20次
[narrator] The average person takes 12 to 20 breaths a minute,
‎但将呼吸减少到一分钟六次
but slowing that down to six breaths
‎可以大幅提升你的心率变异性
can significantly increase your HRV.
‎为吸气和呼气计时
Counting the intake and counting the exhale...
‎深呼吸的确让我感觉好了一些
It did make me feel better to do the deep breathing.
‎多加练习会更容易控制呼吸
[narrator] Controlled breathing gets easier with practice.
‎就像锻炼肌肉一样
Like working out your muscles,
‎你可以将自己的神经系统 ‎训练得能承受更大压力
you can train your nervous system to bear more weight.
‎但当你不断面对新的压力源时
But breathing can only get you so far
‎呼吸的功效是有限的
when you're constantly facing new reasons to be stressed.
‎-但是新冠肺炎… ‎-意大利封国
-[reporter 1] But this COVID-19 crisis... -[reporter 2] Italy shut down...
‎…死亡人数
-[reporter 3] Mass layoffs... -[man] ...death count.
[narrator] But you can avoid doing things that may cause unnecessary stress.
‎在其他创伤性事件后观看电视新闻 ‎比如911事件后
Watching more TV news during other traumatic world events, like 9/11,
‎会有更高几率严重焦虑
was associated with higher rates of serious stress.
‎与其紧盯着新闻
Instead of being glued to the news,
‎不如规划一下你获得新闻的方式
just have a plan for how you're gonna get your news.
‎我一天看一次且只看一次新闻
I check the news once a day and once a day only, and that's because
‎这是因为我知道 ‎那天看的其他任何东西
I know that there's nothing else that I'm going to read during the day
‎都不会改变我的行为
that is going to change my behavior.
‎那对我没有任何帮助
It doesn't serve me in any way.
‎这样做会让你更容易
That's gonna make it just a little bit easier
‎抓住当前形势的不确定性
for you to hold on to the uncertainty of this situation.
‎其他流行的应对方式也并不会帮到你
[narrator] Some other popular coping mechanisms don't serve you, either,
‎比如喝酒
like drinking.
‎疫情初期
When the pandemic started,
‎美国的酒类销量激增
alcohol sales skyrocketed in the US,
‎英国
and in the UK,
‎德国、俄罗斯、芬兰和中国 ‎都是如此
and Germany, and Russia, and Finland, and China.
‎喝酒也许可以缓解当下的焦虑
Drinking may ease the stress in the moment,
‎但酗酒 长远看来会破坏身体的平衡
but heavy drinking in the long term can mess with your body's balance
‎让你更难感觉平静
and make it harder to feel calm.
‎我们有了一个情绪 我们不想面对它
[Gottlieb] We have a feeling, we don't want to feel the feeling,
and those things will immediately obliterate the feeling.
‎然而问题在于 麻木不等于不存在
And the problem with that is that numbness isn't nothingness.
‎麻木是因为情绪太多无法承受
Numbness is being overwhelmed by too many feelings.
‎想要平静 你必须找回对情绪的控制
[narrator] To be calm, you need to take back control of your feelings.
‎精神恢复中很重要的一点是
Something that's really important in resiliency
‎你感觉能从某种程度上掌控你的人生
is feeling like you have some type of control in your life,
‎有一些掌控力
some type of agency.
‎而我们很多人的掌控力都被剥夺了
And this is the exact thing that has been torn away from so many of our lives.
‎我们可能会下意识地憎恨不确定性
[narrator] We may even be hardwired to hate uncertainty.
‎在一项研究中 ‎科学家让人们玩一个简单的游戏
In one study, scientists had people play a simple game,
‎同时检测他们的压力
while measuring their stress.
‎给玩家看一块石头
Players were shown a rock,
‎让他们猜测下面有没有蛇
told to guess whether there was a snake under that rock,
‎然后把石头翻过来
and then to turn it over.
‎如果下面有蛇 他们会被轻轻电一下
If there was a snake, they got a small electric shock.
[electricity zapping]
‎蛇的出现是有规律可循的
The snakes appeared in a kind of pattern.
‎有一些石头下面总是有蛇
Some rocks would always have a snake under them,
‎有一些石头下面从来没有蛇
some would never have a snake under them,
‎其他石头下面有时候有蛇
and others would have a snake sometimes.
‎令人惊讶的是
And the surprising thing was,
‎压力峰值并不会出现在 ‎玩家知道自己会被电击的时候
stress didn't spike when players knew they were going to get shocked.
‎而会出现在他们不确定 ‎会不会被电击的时候
It spiked when they weren't sure whether the shock was coming.
‎这就是这场疫情格外艰难的原因
And that's what makes this pandemic uniquely difficult.
‎我们不知道电击会不会来 ‎什么时候会来
We don't know what shocks are coming, or when.
‎我能回去工作吗？ ‎一切会恢复正常吗？
Am I gonna go back to my job? Is everything gonna be normal?
‎我会感染吗？我会生病吗？
Am I gonna catch it? Am I gonna get sick?
‎你得面对各种焦虑
Like, it's a lot of anxiety you're dealing with.
‎你要保持身体健康
You're dealing with maintaining your well-being,
‎同时还需要保持你的生活方式
but you also have to deal with maintaining, like, your lifestyle.
‎你要付房租 付清账单
You have to pay rent, you have to pay bills.
‎怎么可能专注？
How can you focus?
‎这就要说到第三种方式
[narrator] Which brings us to number three.
‎重获掌控力
Reclaim agency.
‎当整个世界变得完全无法预料
Once the world becomes completely unpredictable,
‎你就要为自己创造一个可预料的世界
you have to create somewhat of a predictable world for yourself.
‎很小的事情也会有帮助
[narrator] Even small things can help,
‎比如按时间表做事
like keeping a schedule.
‎这会让我们有目标感
That gives us a sense of purpose.
‎“我现在为什么在做这件事？”
"Why am I doing what I'm doing in this moment?"
‎它会让我们有价值感 ‎因为我们必须把事情完成
And it gives us a sense of value knowing that we have to get things done,
‎我们必须去哪里
we have to be somewhere.
‎我即使在休息日
But I definitely, even on my days off,
‎也一定有规律地生活 会按时起床
try to keep the routines of getting up at a set time and
‎将想做的事情列成一个表
keeping a list of the things that I want to do
‎这样就不会觉得一天过得很无序
so that it just doesn't feel like this amorphous day.
‎这会帮助我们做好事情
[narrator] It can help to take care of something.
‎这是我的小健身房
I have my, uh, little gym here,
‎还有我的猫
and my cat.
‎看我的猫多漂亮
-You can see my beautiful cat. -[meows]
Huh? [chuckles]
‎或者做些东西
[narrator] Or make something.
‎我在设计东西的时候 会感觉更平静
I just feel, like, more at peace when I'm, like, designing stuff again.
‎在疫情之前 ‎阿约计划卖掉他的一些作品
[narrator] Before the pandemic,
Ayo had planned to sell some of his designs,
‎四月份的时候 他做到了
and in April, he did.
‎我卖掉了我的文化衫 捐赠了20%的钱
I sold my shirts and gave 20% from each shirt to charity,
‎因为虽然我能处理好自己的事情
because although I'm, like, kind of, like, dealing with my own stuff now,
‎但不能忘记还有其他 ‎仍然需要帮助的人
I can't forget that other people do still need help.
‎帮助他人会开启大脑的奖励系统
[narrator] Helping people engages our brain's reward system
‎让我们的皮质醇水平骤降
and makes our levels of cortisol,
‎这是最主要的压力激素之一
one of the main stress hormones, plummet.
‎科学家管这种感觉叫做“助人快感”
Scientists call this sensation "the helper's high,"
‎它不仅让你感觉良好 ‎还对身体有好处
and it doesn't just feel good, it's good for you.
‎有很大的好处
Really good for you.
‎一项研究常年跟踪调查一群老年人
One study checked on a group of older people over several years.
‎研究发现 做志愿活动对长寿的帮助
It found that volunteering had a larger effect on longevity
‎比每周锻炼四次更大
than exercising four times a week,
‎它的影响力跟不抽烟
and the impact was almost as great as not smoking.
‎这就引出了第四个方式
Which brings us to number four.
‎将注意力从自己身上移开
Shift the focus away from yourself.
‎这次疫情让我们明白
Part of what the pandemic has brought to us is
‎我们社会的哪些东西是不可行的
a revelation about what was not working in our society.
‎我们的很多压力并不来源于 ‎可以自行解决的
[narrator] A lot of ours stresses right now aren't individual problems
‎个体的问题
that we can solve individually.
‎它们比这更宏大
They're bigger than that.
‎包括失业 食品安全的隐患
[Nelson] These include unemployment, the potential for food insecurity,
‎人们能否拥有医疗资源和医疗保险
whether or not one has access to healthcare resources and health insurance.
‎我们和公共医疗系统的 ‎兄弟姐妹们站在一起
[woman] We stand here with our brothers and sisters in the public health system.
‎我认为我们明白了 ‎人们很需要医疗保险
I think we're learning that people do need health insurance,
‎他们需要可预见性
they need to have predictability,
‎他们需要有一种社会感觉： ‎“根本而言 我很重要”
and they need to have a social feeling that, "Fundamentally, I matter."
‎如果你无法捐款 你可以捐出时间
[narrator] If you can't give money, you can donate your time,
‎或者血液
or blood,
‎或者技能
or skills.
‎看看你社区中的其他人
See what other people in your neighborhood...
‎你能怎样帮助他们
How you can help them.
‎你能如何帮助你社群中的人们
Like, see how you can help people in that community.
‎不要害怕需要帮助的邻居们
Don't be afraid of your neighbors in this time of need.
‎我觉得每个人都需要团结在一起
Like, I think everybody, kind of, needs to, like, band together
‎互相照应
and look out for each other.
At the beginning of March, I had like, maybe,
‎我主要发狗的照片
250 Instagram followers, and I mostly posted about dogs.
‎但在菲欧娜生病后 ‎她开始发关于病情的内容
[narrator] But when Fiona got sick, she started posting about that instead.
‎我的照片墙开始涌入大量关注者
When I started getting, like, this huge influx of followers
‎人们会私信我询问我的症状
and people DM-ing me asking about my symptoms
‎分享他们自己的经验
and sharing their own experiences,
‎我决定组织一个互助小组
I decided to start a support group.
‎他们来自全世界各地
And they're from all over the world
‎他们处于病毒感染的不同阶段
and they're in all different stages in the virus.
‎由于大家处在不同的时区
And because people are in different time zones,
‎这样一来
you know, it makes it possible
‎人们在半夜醒来的时候 ‎都总会有朋友陪伴
for someone who wakes up in the middle of the night to always have a friend.
‎我们渴望连结 这就是我们
We're wired for connection. That's who we are. That's our nature.
‎大脑的存在是为了和其他人交流
Our brain is there to be involved with other people.
‎历经千百万年的进化
[narrator] Through millions of years of evolution,
‎我们懂得了 独自面对威胁
we've learned that facing threats alone
‎比拥有团队支持的时候更加危险
was more dangerous than if you had the backing of a group.
‎和恐惧一样 共情能力也有适应性
Just like fear is adaptive, so is empathy.
‎我们发现自己常常在努力地
We find ourselves increasingly in a situation
‎创造、培养、想象
in which we're trying to, I think,
‎各种独处和连结的形式
create, cultivate, imagine different forms of solidarity and connection.
‎-嗨！ ‎-嗨！
-Hi! -Hi!
‎-嗨 爸爸 ‎-嗨
-Hi, Dad. -Hi.
‎我认为那次下午七点的欢呼 ‎是它的一种表现形式
I think that 7:00 p.m. cheer is another manifestation of that.
[cheering, pots clanging]
‎人们走出来 ‎为必不可缺的工作者欢呼
[Kathryn] It may seem silly that people go outside
‎虽然看起来可能有些蠢
and continue to cheer for essential workers.
‎但让我觉得非常震撼
But that is just mind-blowing to me.
[horn honking]
‎有人在群里发了一条很感人的消息
Someone posted in the group this just beautiful message
‎关于她怎样意识到…
about how she had realized that...
‎“我的身体和我 ‎为生存而战而且取得了胜利
"My body and I, like, we fought for our lives and we won.
‎所以我真的不应该勉强自己
So I really shouldn't be pushing myself at all.
‎我能做的就是见证 ‎下一个了不起的阶段
All I can do is, like, witness the next incredible phase of this thing,
‎也就是我身体的恢复过程
which is my body's healing process.
‎我的身体知道该怎么做 ‎它带领我走到这一步
My body knows what to do 'cause it got me this far.
‎我现在能做的就是让它主导”
All I can do right now is kind of let it take the lead."
‎我发誓 我读完那些文字就哭了出来
I swear, I just started sobbing when I read those words
‎我太能感同身受了
because it resonated so much with me.
‎另一方面
[narrator] Going through this together
‎一起撑过这次疫情 ‎也许能让世界更富同情心
may make for a more compassionate world on the other side.
‎2003年的非典疫情之后
After the SARS epidemic in 2003,
‎研究人员调查了香港居民
researchers surveyed residents of Hong Kong,
‎受非典影响最严重的城市之一
one of the cities that had been hardest hit.
‎三分之二的人说
Almost two-thirds of them said
‎他们比以往更在意家人的情绪
they cared more about their family's feelings than they did before,
‎几乎同样数量的人说
and around the same number said
‎他们更在意自己的心理健康状况
they paid more attention to their mental health.
‎其实寻求心理帮助并没有特定的标准
There isn't really a line that you need to cross to go get help.
‎如果你感觉：“我发现自己不太舒服
If you feel like, "You know what? I'm having trouble functioning
‎跟平时的状态不一样”
in the way that I normally function,"
‎就去寻求帮助
go get help.
‎心理治疗师能给你工具
Therapists can give you tools
‎帮助你应对焦虑 不管是什么
to help you cope with stresses, whatever they are.
‎应对方式不是放之四海而皆准的
[narrator] Coping is not one-size-fits-all.
‎（阿黛沙 印度）
[in Hindi] We work on our garden every evening.
‎要寻找最适合你的方式
[narrator] It's about figuring out what works for you.
‎我在做早就想做的手工项目
I've been going through my DIY hitlist I've had for too long,
‎做我以前就该做的事情
doing all the jobs that I meant to do.
‎我每天早上会整理床铺
I made my bed every morning.
‎你看 就在这里
You can see right here.
‎看 今天铺好了
See, it's made today.
‎每天早上好好打扮 调整好情绪
Really get dressed and kind of put myself together in the morning.
‎我每天都有小目标
I have little goals every day,
‎上跑步机 在公寓里走走
to get on the treadmill, to walk around the apartment.
‎按照计划表做 能帮助我度过每一天
And if I keep that schedule, it helps me get through each day.
‎整理我的乐高收藏 搭乐高
[Aman] Organize my Lego collection. Build some Lego.
‎（费尔南多）
[in Brazilian Portuguese] I really enjoyed making this mask and drawing again.
‎我做烩饭的手艺精进了
I have perfected the risotto.
‎锻炼对我来说是解压的好办法
Exercise is a great stress reliever for me,
‎出去跑步 累的时候就走走
so going for runs, or just long walks if I'm exhausted.
‎我想永远保持那天的感激之情
I never want to lose the gratitude, um, that I had
‎出院之后 我走回我家的街区
on that day that I got released from the hospital and that I walked...
‎再次看到我的房子
back down my block and saw my house again.
‎抱歉
Sorry. [sniffles]
‎我的大部分家人住在意大利
My family lives in Italy, a lot of them, and we've been doing a lot of group Zooms,
‎我们会一起唱歌
and we've been singing over them.
‎它帮助我们缓解了很大的压力
That's been, like, such a source of relief for everyone.
[all singing in Italian]
[Jess laughing]
‎唱歌的确非常抚慰人心
[narrator] Which may actually be particularly soothing.
‎很多形式的音乐都能减轻焦虑
There are a lot of different things about music that reduce stress.
‎大合唱就是其中的一种
One of them is group singing.
[people singing in Italian]
‎我们不知道具体是什么原理
[Levitin] We don't know exactly what's going on,
‎但有初步证据表明 当我们合唱时
but there's some early evidence that when we sing together,
‎我们的脑电波会和一起唱歌的人同步
our brain waves synchronize with the other people we're singing with,
‎释放催产素 能让我们有连结感
oxytocin is released, which helps us to feel bonded to them,
‎我们观察到 在合唱的时候 ‎人们的压力激素水平会降低
and we've seen the stress hormone levels drop when people sing together.
[all singing]
‎我们的机能就是这样
That's how we're wired. What do you do when you have a baby?
[music playing on speaker]
‎你们一起唱歌 一起摇摆
You sing together, you rock together. That's our nature.
[man singing]
‎我们就是这样的 我们天生如此
[van der Kolk] That's how we are formed, that's how we are made.
‎压力能帮助我们生存
[narrator] Stress is there to help us survive.
[cheers, applause]
‎应对能帮助我们生活
[narrator] Coping is to help us live.
‎要是觉得难以承受
So if it gets overwhelming, just remember...
‎吸气 吐气
-breathe in... -[deep inhale]
-...breathe out. -[exhale]
[theme music playing]